staple.
係啊。
五分鐘。
都要開嘅。
呀。
唔緊要啦。
哇！乜個都喺度。
呢度開始先㗎嘛，司長咪。
第二次嘅會議。
唔緊要，我用英文駕駛都得啊！全部。
誒，得。
有咩問題嗰度即係嗰個嗰steps？
係冇乜嘢唔可以畀人聽到㗎嘛，係咪？
我好奇怪，點解佢而家有兩支麥嘅？馮生做主席位都喺啲喺conference room。
早晨，各位委員，咁咧就我宣佈咧係夠法定人數。今日係二零一七年税務修訂第二號條例草案委員會嘅。
嗯，我哋而家咧就第一個議程咧就係誒一啲嘅團體咧係就呢一條條例草案係去發表意見嘅。噉我誒請咗誒我哋嘅誒與會嘅團體代表同埋政府啊代表入嚟先啦。嚇，唔該曬。
有佢有曬啲。
不過佢應該都夠時間畀個回覆啦，係嘛？我都。
立法會權力及特權條例所保障嘅。
你哋嘅口頭陳述同埋書面陳述咧，係唔會受到。
Channel number two will be the English channel. We have simultaneous interpretation for English in channel number two.
該須知咧已經夾附咗喺秘書處發給各位嘅函件之中，亦都放咗喺誒各位嘅枱面上面。
Have sat with you. Channel number zero will be the live broadcast. Channel number one will be Cantonese channel.
好，另外咧，我要提醒各位與會人士咧，除咗誒，今天喺呢一度出席嘅立法會議員同埋誒指定嘅官員之外咧，出席今日誒會議嘅其他人士咧。
誒，另外誒，想提醒各位與會嘅人士啦，啊，留意喺立法會綜合大樓會議室出席會議同埋喺公眾席旁聽會議嘅公眾人士須之中列出嘅各項嘅保安措施。
會話嘅時間係會係五分鐘嘅。嗱，你哋發言嘅時候咧，只需指出你意見書嘅重點，而無需復述意見書嘅全部內容。因為咧，我哋亦都誒嘅委員同埋秘書處都有機會係睇到你哋嘅誒書面陳述嘅內容嘅。
And we have the Putonghua translation, simultaneous translation in channel number three. So if anyone who does not understand any languages, you can just put up the headphone and ask our concierge to to assist you if you you want.
Good morning, everyone, and welcome to the second meeting of the Two Hundred and One Seven Inland Revenue Amendment Number Two Bill Committee. Just for clarification, I will just do a very brief introduction in English, but the rest of the meeting will be conducted in Cantonese. And if you have your
啊！旁聽嘅公眾人士幾多向在場保安人士索取有關嘅數字？應該就今日冇啊旁聽嘅人士啦。嗱，我而家咧就會誒請議會代表咧係逐一發言，而我畀每位嘅時間，因為由於呢一個條例草案都非常之技術性咧，我畀。
啊！而根據嘅慣常做法咧，我哋委員會咧係將收到嘅書面意見書咧係會上載喺立法會嘅網頁，亦都已經係發給曬畀啊呢一個委員會嘅委員。嗱，如果各位未有意見書或者有啲補充嘅文件咧，歡迎喺會後。
講嘅發展嘅。
公司租任飛機使用嘅。
帶嚟誒裨益嘅。
為香港咧，爬緊機遇。
航空公司對飛嘅需求咧殷切。
全球嘅飛機租賃業咧，亦都會繼續迅速擴張嘅。
呢個法案咧，而家呢個法案咧，提出對香港嘅飛機租賃公司。
本法案咧可以為飛機租賃業喺香港發展創造合適嘅條件。
為飛機租賃業咧喺香港發展咧，創造一個具競競爭力嘅營商環境。
將會對香港嘅經濟發展帶嚟好處嘅，我哋咧係對法案咧呢個法案咧係表示支持嘅。多謝。
嘅跨境飛機租任活動咧，給予優惠嘅税務安排，係可以使到香港咧擺脱歷史遺留下來嘅枷鎖。
市場咧預測未來二十年咧，全球航空客運嘅需求咧，尤其喺亞太區，包括中國大陸咧，每年增長迅速。
誒根據咧愛爾蘭嘅經驗咧，飛機租賃業咧為當地咧帶嚟高質素嘅就業機會，亦都促進咧金融啊、法律啊、會計等商業活動對經濟咧。
目前咧，愛爾蘭同埋新加坡咧係全球主要嘅飛機租任公司，誒誒租任中心。尤尤其係愛爾蘭咧，主要嘅國際飛機租任公司咧，都喺愛爾蘭咧設立基地，進行飛機租任業務。
提供啊！此外咧，我想誒提醒大家發言時候咧，誒你可以用中文或者單純用英文打，就最好唔好就係誒夾雜中英文，因為方便我哋嘅誒傳譯人員嘅嘅工作啊！噉我就而家先請誒誒Mr。
William Ho啊，Mr. Ho唔該你有五分鐘嘅時間嚇。係主席，誒，全球嘅航空客運業增長迅速，航航空公司咧不時需要擴充和更新機隊嘅飛機咧係非常昂貴嘅資產。航空公司除咗購買飛機以外咧，會從飛機租任。
啊，香港咧，大約喺三十年前咧，曾經修改税務法例，成功地打擊當時被濫用嘅香港飛機共幹租任活動，但係咧，亦都係遺留下來一啲嘅副作用，窒礙咗飛機租任業喺香港。
唔該曬。誒，下一位係誒Miss Carrie Liu from Baker McKenzie，應該。Okay. Um, so on behalf of Baker McKenzie, we are supportive of this Inland Revenue Amendment Number Two Bill as well, and we also believe it does help to remove the tax impediments that the the current regime.
到處，税額免税是提供於一個條約。
Written submissions, the one that we want to raise in particular is the definition of non-Hong Kong.
feedback we have from clients that the changes that we are presenting for for the industry players are actually very attractive commercially.
香港，how easy it is to to have that management in Hong Kong, and also not having a PE outside of Hong Kong. Again, whether or not you might want to.
Whether or not capital expenditure would also include expenses incurred under a funding lease, that point is not clear. Whether or not we might have clarification on that.
at the moment there is so that that provision allows for the eighty percent deemed deduction, and there are a number of conditions that needs to be satisfied. One of them is the
其他地區，such as Singapore and Island， they don't have that distinguish distinction between the two。 whether or not there is a need for that for the Hong Kong regime， we do question that。
Think about maybe having a grace period that would allow people to transition in into the regime, or before they get used to how how it actually operates. And finally, just on again on section 14I3A.
has in attracting Hong Kong to a more a more palatable commercially palatable commercial aircraft leasing hub for international players, especially for leasing company looking to base in Ireland and Singapore. So we've done a comparison with other regimes, and we also think just based on.
There are a few minor issues that we want to raise about the bills. Most of these, we we actually have the benefit of looking at the written submissions that made by other parties that are present at this meeting, and a lot of our submissions in terms of our comments are pretty much aligned with with those that are presented in.
航空運輸業者，我們同意其他提呈人。在方面，我們需要檢討定義。目前，它説它只適用於航空運輸業者，他們不適用於香港的税務和國內規則。我們同意，您可能需要檢討擴展。
The other comments that were also raised by other submissions are whether or not at the moment the regime only applies when the aircraft they saw is leasing to an operating lessee. Whether or not there is a need to distinguish between what you call under legislation a funding lease versus an operating lease.
地位。
市場裏邊。
我表示支持。
That has flights flying to Hong Kong for uplift of passengers or goods.
That's it. Okay, thank you. 啊，下一位係啊。
英國安理國際會計師誒國際律師事務所嘅何遠文女士唔該。
in this regard, we will appreciate if the government can clarify whether this is the legislative legislative intent.
好唔該，下一位係誒Association of Chartered Certified Accountants嘅誒誒倪先生，誒先生唔該你。
The leasing transaction concerned will not be covered by the regime because the overseas airline will be chargeable to profits tax under the inland revenue ordinance and therefore not being regarded as a non-Hong Kong aircraft operator.
as for the details of the regime, we would like to seek the government's view or clarification on the following three points. some some of these points may have already mentioned by by the other representatives.
首先，根據現時定義的非香港機場運營商在法案中，顯然如果一資格的香港機場租户租用機場給海外航空公司，
at all， and you would effectively be subject to 8.25 tax rate instead of the lower concession. Again, whether or not there might be any room for considering for for this this this condition not to be imposed where aircraft is transferred at arm's length value.
主席，首先，我代表ACCA，我們願表達我們對政府推動引入減税優惠機制，為機械租賃業界在港的大力支持。我們相信，此機制有助吸引更多機械租賃及管理業務來港。
另一個是，又跟著融資租賃。如果我們要追蹤這條線，我們要排除融資租賃。目前《第十四I三A》條款規定，飛機租賃必須發生飛機租賃的相關開支，以提供飛機租賃。
The other point, probably one minor one, just on at the moment the region doesn't have any grace period. And some of the senators also commented on the condition about the control and management exercise in Hong Kong, whether or not for new leasing platform that just established in Hong.
the the aircraft must not have been claimed capital allowance by a connected person. again, we're wondering if you would whether or not that that condition needs to be applied, because from our perspective, it probably would be an issue if you've got a connected parties arrangement where the aircraft is leased at below, say, the market value.
但係，如果如果The transaction actually occurred at market value of the aircraft， read or not， there is still that sort of exclusion， because it's an absolute exclusion。 and once the aircraft has been has had capital allowance claimed by by a connected person previously， you would not be allowed that that you know to come within the regime。
誒，作為飛機租任行業嘅參與者，我一路係見到飛機租任行業嘅發展，無論係喺航空公司用租任嘅方式去持有飛機，又或者係新嘅租任公司嘅成立，或者係涉及租任公司嘅交易咧。其實誒，近年一直都有增長，特別係喺中國個。
飛機租用行業對於資金啦、高端技術啦同埋服務咧，係有好大嘅需求。周邊會衍生好多融資、拼購資產、轉讓管理、保險嗰啲交易嘅需求，可以帶動行業嘅發展，亦都會加強香港作為國際金融中心嘅。
啊！呢個條例嘅修訂可以令到香港嘅税務環境對於飛機租賃公司更加有吸引力，故同世界其他兩個主要嘅飛機租賃中心可以誒更加接近，再結合香港嘅優勢，會有助香港發展成為國際飛機租賃中心。我哋對呢個發
用嗰個飛機折舊。
作為其中嘅一個啊啊！
and also in the case where the overseas airline is exempt from profits tax under the applicable Hong Kong tax treaty.
第二，under the current bill， one of the condition to qualify for the regime is that the lessee must be an aircraft operator.
會唔會被 regard as not being not chargeable to profits tax and does qualifying as a non-Hong Kong aircraft operator?
We would like to seek the government's view on whether, in the above situation, it will look at the overseas airline group as a whole and treat aircrafts as being leased to an aircraft operator.
We believe doing so will also enhance the transparency of the regime. That's all for ACC's submission. Thank you very much. Okay, thank you, Ms. Zhang. The next one will be Ms. Ho Hon Chungfa, the president of Hong Kong Aircraft Leasing and Aviation Finance Association.
誒，事實上誒，呢個比例大概嚟講咧，以前係零，但係而家租任咧去到大概四十，甚至將來嘅幾年咧去到百分之五十左右嘅。喺誒內地嚟講咧，早時早時咧都有個文件出嚟咧，係特別去加快國內。
as we understand that in some cases and for commercial reasons, an aircraft lessor may lease aircraft to a special purpose vehicle set up within an overseas airline group, and then for this special purpose vehicle to sublease the aircraft to the aircraft operator within the same airline group.
finally, we recommended that a departmental interpretation and practice note be issued by the Inland Revenue Department to set out its views on the interpretation and application of the various key provisions of the regime, including the two points mentioned above, so as to provide greater certainty and clarity to taxpayers.
多謝啊，主席，我係代表香港飛機租任同埋航空呢個融資協會，就呢個二零一七年税務修訂第二號條例草案啊，發表我哋嘅睇法、我哋嘅意見嘅。根據呢個啊飛機製造商嘅預測，而呢個預測咧，基本上我諗喺航空界嚟講，基本上都係認同嘅。就喺將來個。
在 mainland China，在 next 20 years。
which is estimated to be approximately US seven hundred and sixty million, which is a large sum of money.
所以，for those let's say who who wants to set up a base in in Asia, they are looking at Hong Kong.
However, under the current tax law in Hong Kong, as commented by some other representatives in this meeting today.
國際航空勒索爾， has been looking to develop an Asian base to serve their Asian customers.
PwC is totally supportive of this bill, and we will echo the Hong Kong government's observation of the potential demand of new aircraft.
Given Hong Kong's unique position to Hong Kong, its prominent role as a business hub in the region, sophisticated financial markets and well-developed legal system.
會係全力支持誒誒呢個條例草案。多謝主席。啊，Thank you, Mr. Ho。 The next one will be Mr. Loong Kai Fai from Price Waterhouse Cooper's Limited。 Thank you。
主席，PwC welcomes the opportunity to comment on the captain build to create a dedicated tax regime to attract aircraft lessor to come to Hong Kong.
為誒銀行、資本、股票市場、資產管理、法律、税務、會計、企業服務等等嘅行業帶嚟嘅聯動嘅效應，促進整體經濟嘅增長。啊，呢個增強化香港作為國際主要金融同埋航空中心嘅地位。
二十年裏邊嘅飛機嘅交付量咧，大概係去到差唔多四萬架，而且而家總價值咧去到大概係六萬億美元噉樣嘅價值嘅。當然，其中最主要嘅增長亦都係亞太區。亞太區裏邊嘅當中最其中最重要咧，係中國內地咧，係個嗰個。
啊！航空量嘅增長咧，每年咧係大概六啊六個percent左右嘅。啊，近年嚟嘅，事實上喺過去咁多年嚟嘅咧，係航空公司咧出現一個好大嘅趨勢咧，就從原來嘅係買飛機咧，到而家咧逐步逐步咧，一部分咧係呢個啊用呢個啊呢個租飛機嘅形式嘅啊。
即係中國大陸裏邊嘅飛機租任市場業務嘅發展，譬如佢幾個啊漸茂區啦，譬如天津啊、上海啊，我哋旁邊嘅田啊、前海啊等等嚇，都係誒呢個基本上顯示呢個業務發展係相當之快嘅。目前事實上喺世界裏邊咧，最主要嘅飛機租任中。
心咧係啊，愛爾蘭同埋啊，某程度嚟講咧，新加坡，但係就係愛爾蘭為主嘅最大嘅，因為佢哋對呢個飛機租任業務咧係提供咗非常之優惠嘅啊政策，所以可以可以講話喺呢個行業裡面嘅標杆嘅一個啊一個國家嘅一個啊政策嚟。
咁根據現行嘅一個税制咧，香港喺從事飛機租用業務咧，誒實際上嚟講，如果係從嗰個計數方面睇咧，係實在需要繳交嘅税率係比個標準税率十六點五仲要高一倍有多嘅。其實原因就因為目前呢個誒誒税制裏邊嚟講咧，你唔可以claim即係。
啊，一個一個對比噉樣嘅啊，減呢個減載嘅成本去減咗佢嘅，咁所以顯著咧係高於其他嘅地方啊。所以嚴格嚟講咧，實際上目前香港呢個行業係唔存在嘅呢個。誒，香港當然係啊，我哋係背近喺隔離咧，我有個非常之大嘅市市場，就係中國內地啦。
咁所以香港作為呢個作個國際金融、航空、物流中心啊，我哋有優良嘅融資啦、誒税務啦、會計嘅配套啦、航空基礎設施啦、人才啦，同埋完善嘅法律制度，誒應該我哋係絕對有條件係成為一個國際租飛機租。
公司設立基地嘅理想地點啊，所以我哋誒作為個協會、行業協會認為咧，條例草案對香港發展呢一方面嘅業務咧係必須嘅，係呢個誒建議嘅新嘅税制之下嚟講咧，將來飛機租賃公司嘅税務負擔將會呢個。
大大拉近同其他嘅地方嘅一個距離，香港更加有機會，更加佢會吸引到國際公司嚟香港設立飛機租用平台，開展一方面嘅業務。當然啦，我哋都係希望，同時咧，都係呢個業務都係需要呢個香港政府喺個政策上繼續支持，尤其是係特別咧，就係擴大。
同埋優化香港同其他國家啊簽訂嘅啊避免雙重啊呢個啊呢個徵税協議，即係所謂嘅D T A。啊，飛機租賃業務咧，為香港係直接間接啊創造咧，會非常之多嘅租高價高價值嘅就職位，同時亦都會。
所以誒，協會相信本條例嘅草案同埋特區政府對飛機租賃行業嘅政策支持，將會令到國際飛機租賃公司認真考慮以香港作為佢哋開展誒進一步誒呢個呢個誒發展呢個業務嘅基地。所以誒，本協會。
The effective tax rate.
我會 also actually like to comment.
In my own opinion, is a welcome move.
annoted under the new rules.
at the moment, there's no aircraft leasing business in Hong Kong.
which in my opinion is unreasonable and unjustifiable.
這 type of business to establish their leasing business activities in Hong Kong.
According to a research paper entitled "Aviation Leasing, Leverage Hong Kong Strength."
When taking into account the latest developments, the base erosion and profit shifting led by the OECD initiative.
The effect of actually paying a little bit of tax, as compare to defer the tax payment in the future years.
hence, we welcome the Hong Kong government's recent decisions to actually amend the Hong Kong tax rules in order to attract.
We've actually thought the poll tax regime by the Hong Kong government is very innovative.
for aircraft lessor to carry on leasing business Hong Kong， would be far lower than our major competitors in the other region.
This will not only help Hong Kong maintain its competitiveness as Asia's key transportation and business hub, but also strengthen its positions as a major international financial centre.
The effective tax rate under the current rules for doing for carrying aircraft leasing business in Hong Kong is well over 30%, as compared to the Hong Kong standard rate of profit tax 16.5.
我們會comment，任何這樣的税則修改，應該不會導致香港任何税負增加。將香港發展成一架機租賃、融資和投資中心，應該不需要香港政府補貼，正如其他代表所建議的。
hence.
In addition, uncertainty within the legislation also discourages multinationals.
Based on the new aircraft required globally from the aircraft manufacturer.
And most importantly, I think is to create jobs for the future generation. Thank you.
Published by Peterpiece Hong Kong in 2017，we actually we actually estimated。
If Hong Kong decides to turn into an aviation leasing hub, we believe in the next 20 years.
It can be over 3,000 aircraft, with a value of approximately 91 billion.
The policy intention behind each of these changes has been sound, and these are policy changes which other jurisdictions have successfully implemented in the past.
Thank you, Mr. Lo. The next speaker will be Mr. Calver from Dilloy Advisory Hong Kong Limited. Thank you, Chairman.
However, in each of these cases, the legislation introduced has not had the effect intended and has not resulted in significant increased activity in Hong Kong.
税法立法可能並非唯一要考慮的因素。然而，税法立法在每一個情況下都過於繁瑣，要遵守，且缺乏確定性，即使在一個相當複雜的情況下。
incentive legislation which is onerous to comply with is unlikely to attract a multinational to relocate their activities to Hong Kong, particularly when they are likely to already locate their activities in a jurisdiction offering favourable tax treatment.
We believe the establishment of Hong Kong as an important is an important aircraft leasing centre will therefore help to promote and consolidate Hong Kong's position as a global business and financial centre.
Thank you, Chairman. Deloitte's key technical points have already been made by other speakers. Our technical points have also been included in our written submission. I would like to use this time to emphasise the importance of rectifying the drafting issues which have been identified.
While a reasonable degree of uncertainty is acceptable, legislation must be drafted to provide sufficient certainty such that core policy objectives are met without it being necessary for the inland revenue department to issue guidance notes in order to provide comfort to the industry on how legislation will work in practice.
在過去幾年，香港已推出多項立法，以鼓勵從香港進行的活動，並改善香港的經濟地位及作為全球金融中心的地位，包括措施吸引伊斯蘭金融、企業財務活動及發行可抵扣的額外Tier One資本給金融機構。
unless, in the commissioner's view, it is reasonable, consider this option may not be exercised.
這係即使在適用適用的條約來 exempte 非香港飛機運營商從繳納税款。
The combination of onerous and uncertain legislation discourages companies from relocating their activities to Hong Kong.
In addition, the definition of lease in the bill appears to exclude certain finance leases, which have the option to transfer aircraft during the period of the lease.
At a time when the UK has consistently reduced its corporate tax rate, the US is contemplating a corporate tax rate cut to 15% or 20%.
We believe the proposed regime should enhance our tax competitiveness, and should be implemented as soon as possible.
And Singapore already offers low tax rates and a raft of incentives. Companies have other options, and Hong Kong is in the position of having to compete.
Based on the current drafting of the bill, it does not appear this is the case. Several examples have been outlined in our written submission and touched on by other committee members here.
而至於機場的運作，則是政府的職責。
Due to this unprecedented tax competition, it is important that legislation should be drafted in a manner which is easy to comply with, and provides certainty in order to give rise to the underlying policy intent.
doing so puts the Nam Revenue Department in a difficult position of balancing their objectives of protecting the tax base with interpreting legislation in a manner which will allow taxpayers to take advantage of intended incentives.
In particular, the definition of non-Hong Kong aircraft operator, in combination with section 23D of the IRO, appears to prevent an aircraft operator which lands in Hong Kong from being a lessee within the meaning of the bill.
While there appear to be drafting issues with the bill, we believe the overall policy measures intended by the bill should sufficiently improve Hong Kong's position as aircraft leasing centre, in particular with regard to China. We are supportive of the bill provided drafting issues can be rectified. Thank you.
Thank you, and the next speaker will be Mr. Jeremy Choi from the Taxation Institute of Hong Kong. Thank you, Chairman. The T.I.H.K. support the government initiative to introduce the tax regime to promote aircraft leasing and financing industry.
perhaps unsurprisingly, tax professionals and industry participants often comment that IRD guidance is often skewed towards protecting the tax base. While IRD guidance is not binding, when there are significant areas of uncertainty or the legislation provides for the commissioner to provide their view, as is the case in the bill, taxpayers give significant weight to this guidance.
多謝主席。
要繳付税款，under the ordinance.
It would appease that the Hong Kong qualifying aircraft lessor who enter into finance arrangement.
However, many overseas aircraft operator would have some of their aircraft flying to Hong Kong to uplift passengers and goods.
Now, as such, finance arrangements are not uncommon in the aircraft leasing and financing industry.
such overseas aircraft operator would likely be chargeable to profit tax in Hong Kong as a non-resident under the current regulation.
Well, unless the commissioner is in the opinion that the aircraft concerned would reasonably be expected not to pass to the left sea.
The second point we want to make is based on the current definition of funding lease and lease in the proposed legislation.
或higher purchase agreement with non-Hong Kong aircraft operator will not be eligible for the tax treatment under the concessionary tax regime.
as such, they are technically chargeable to profit tax under the IRO, even though they may be exempted under the treaty or service agreements.
finally， we also recommend the government to issue di-pen notes to set out clearly the the points of this legislation afterwards.
作為Shown in the government's briefings to Ledgeco, there is expected to be a strong growth in the demand for aircraft fleet size over the coming decades, particularly in the mainland, and Hong Kong should be positioning itself to take advantage of all that additional financing activity.
now as such we prefer to suggest the legislation to make it to make it clear that the condition of not chargeable to profit tax under the ordinance would be satisfied where profit are subsequently exempt under the treaty.
We would like to urge the government to consider expanding the scope of concessionary tax regime to cover finance lease arrangement and hire purchase arrangement as well. As in particular, as both tax regime in Ireland and Singapore do not distinguish them.
However, we do have some recommendations as set out in our paper, and some of which has been mentioned by the previous speaker. Number one is the definition of non-Hong Kong aircraft operator. Under the proposed regulations, a non-Hong Kong aircraft operator is defined to mean an aircraft operator who is not charged.
Thank you, Mr. Choi. And the next speaker will be Mr. Albert Lin from the Hong Kong Institute of Certified Public Accountants. Good morning. Firstly, the institute would like to thank the chairman and the committee for inviting us to make representations. The institute fully supports the introduction of a tax concession for aircraft leasing and related services.
嗯。
税 concession， which is for providing services to qualifying aircraft lessors。
incentivising all financing of Hong Kong qualifying lessors rather than just ones that own leasing SPVs.
on this basis, we recommend changing the drafting of the bill to exclude leasing to aircraft operators that are actually subject to profits tax on the profits from their air carriage activities.
Proposed Schedule 17 can never satisfy this requirement. For example, if you look at 1K, which is the activity of providing finance in obtaining the ownership of an aircraft by an airline enterprise from another corporation that is a relevant qualifying aircraft lessor.
However, that discriminates against non-Hong Kong resident companies, for example, foreign companies operating through a Hong Kong branch, and that is specifically prohibited under the non-discrimination articles of Hong Kong's tax treaties with a number of other jurisdictions. So we suggest that that be altered or removed.
However, as we describe in our written submission, the bill as drafted has some serious deficiencies, many of which have been alluded to by the other representatives. I would suggest that these deficiencies should be corrected in the statute, in the legislation itself, rather than relying on non-binding.
Extra statutory guidance from the Inland Revenue. The first and most significant issue with the drafting relates to who can qualify as an aircraft lessor under the tax concession, which has been raised by almost all of the professional representatives here. The concession only applies to qualifying leasing activity.
which only include leasing to a non-Hong Kong aircraft operator, and that's defined as one that is not chargeable to profits tax. The issue is that section 23B of the inland revenue ordinance deems non-Hong Kong resident aircraft operators to be carrying on business in Hong Kong and therefore to be chargeable to profits tax.
If they land any aircraft at a Hong Kong airport, this would seem to exclude most international airlines and many mainland airlines, as surely they all land in Hong Kong occasionally, and limits the usefulness of both the tax concession for aircraft leasing, but also the aircraft leasing management.
There are also a number of issues with the aircraft leasing manager tax concession. To qualify, the aircraft leasing manager must be providing qualifying activities to a qualifying aircraft lessor. However, some of the list of aircraft leasing management activities in.
個數量係相當多㗎，我要指出呢一點。
好，阿趙生唔該你嚇，多謝主席。
香港嘅利得税咧，答案會涵蓋咗嘅。
係包括係喺雙邊嘅税務協議裏邊唔使交。
見咧技術上我哋睇過嘅，其實好多我哋都可以採納，但喺技術層面咧，我哋會要需要時間要寫清楚，就避免咗大家有誤解啊，或者被人濫用嘅熱熱情況嘅啫。
稍後有一個書面嘅回應，但係咧誒喺現在，我畀翻啲時間畀政府官員作出一個誒初步嘅回應先，然後咧我就請誒委員誒向各位團體提問。咁誒阿阿劉生先啦，唔該你係。
香港作為一個飛機租任誒中心嘅一個實力嘅嚇，咁有關誒頭先各位提出一啲嘅具體關於嗰條誒法案裏邊嗰啲細節咧，噉我或者啊，如果主席容許咧，我想透過你就邀請啊誒趙處長啊趙局長咧，可以去誒逐一可以去回應一下嘅嚇。
That's a specific example where you can never satisfy that exemption because an airline can never be a qualifying aircraft lessor, and therefore you can't provide that activity to a qualifying aircraft lessor and obtain the tax concession. Furthermore, the other listed activities in relation
Airline leasing management seem to be overly restricted. So, for example, one C and D are to do with providing finance to qualifying aircraft lessors, but only apply if the person providing the finance owns the leasing SPV. What we suggest would be better is if you're in.
另一個 issue 是要與一個反避税條款有關的法案，這要求有關公司申請税收優惠必須在香港中央管理及控制。我們懷疑這是為了確保公司在香港有足夠實質，並且該制度不被視為濫用。
finally, and again, a lot of the representatives have mentioned this. The definition of lease in the proposed legislation is cumbersome and overly restrictive. The existing definition of lease in the inland revenue ordinance already excludes hire purchase agreements where the ownership of the asset may pass to the lessee. So
It is not clear why a wholly new definition is required for this legislation. But in any case, we would suggest that it shouldn't be restricted to leases where ownership of the aircraft doesn't pass to the lessee. There appear to be no mischief that is being addressed by this, and it will limit commercial leasing arrangements.
We hope the bills committee will seek amendment of the bill so that achieves its purpose. 啊，九鍾啦，啊，唔好意思啊。啊，噉我哋就聽曬誒團體今日嘅意見啦。就誒團體嘅意見，無論係書面意見或口頭意見咧，啊，我都希望政府可以有一個啊。
唔該，多謝主席，亦都想透過主席多謝今日出席呢個誒會議嘅各位代表誒。我哋好高興聽到大家對於呢一個誒法案嘅一個支持。咁誒誒，我哋都同意就係話，其實呢一個法案係能夠誒通過到嘅話咧，係能夠大大增強到。
誒就就頭先各個團體畀咗個意見咧，政税務各方面或者政府都係好歡迎嘅。事實上有好多嘅意見咧，其實都係我哋立法嘅意意向嘅。嗱，比方説最重一點咧，團體話會唔會所謂non-hongkong aircraft operator？
原因點解我哋用個字係用chargeable嗰個英語嗰個字咧？原因咪喺個treaty用嘅字係taxable喺我哋嘅税務條例最相近嘅字就係chargeable。所以換句話講咧，如果有一間海外嘅航空公司喺個雙邊税務協議唔需要徵税嘅，佢就被認為。
有一間not chargeable to Hong Kong profit tax嘅嗰架aircraft operator就會涵蓋裏邊嘅，咁所以因為現時我哋香港咧已經有三十七張嘅簽署咗嘅雙邊税務協議啦，仲有數張嘅誒air services agreement啦，所以現時涵蓋。
啊。
太多時間，係五月二號上晝九點鐘。
不過佢就利用咗個跳板，就跳咗去外國個公司。但係其實佢飛嚟飛去都係飛香港嘅。
咁表面上就睇好似賺曬噉，但係大家唔好唔記得。
即係嗰間公司喺海外個合約海外，但係佢好多嘅飛行嗰個。
人去擁有個飛機，但係佢係透過一間海外嘅公司。
然後嗰架飛機咧，就雖然個合約咧就係喺海外簽，但係佢經常係飛香港嘅。
嗰個被濫用嘅情況嘅啫，咁主席，我同意，我哋稍後時間咧會就團體嘅submission咧會做翻一個正式嘅書面回覆㗎。
香港去為咗建設呢個機場咧，我哋畀咗一個好大嘅premium嘅，即係嗰啲錢落去。而家講緊第三條跑道咧，係一千四百一十五億，呢個唔係真金白銀嘅錢嚟嘅。
你話基地又好，佢嗰個經常個旅程都係經過香港，咁咁呢個咪即係正正造就咗一個税務嘅流動。其實香港係唔係賺多咗税，係收少咗嘅，因為原本呢一啲。
方便我哋咧，係再進行呢個逐條審議嘅時候咧，係再作出詳細嘅討論。嗱，而家以下嘅時間咧，我就交翻畀我哋嘅誒委員會嘅成員。啊，我知阿郭嘉琪醫生啊，有有有有提問嘅，唔該你啊，阿郭醫生。
另外一點咧就誒好團體就話誒原則上我聽到嘅都係支持呢個草案嘅，咁但係佢哋覺得技術上有好多細節都係需要作一個departmental interpretation嘅practice note嘅，咁呢點咧我哋信哥係完全認同嘅。咁團體提出嘅意。
噉就至於仲有一點比較重要嘅就係話嗰個financing lease嗰個問題啦，因為喺税務嗰個誒税基侵蝕同埋利潤轉移咧，我哋留意到咧就國際上咧係要求咧有實體嘅業務喺香港嘅，其實所有嘅。
資產咧最好就喺香港一個居民企業咧就所擁有嘅呢個擁有咧，我哋係已經係擴闊咗佢嘅。我記得主席我都曾經解釋過，我哋而家所講嘅ownership喺呢個regime裏邊咧，其實包含著funding lease誒融融資嘅。
購買啦，包括誒higher purchase啦，同埋亦包括就conditional sale嘅。其實我哋喺嗰個擁有嗰邊咧，就相當闊涵蓋咗嘅。咁而係話再由香港嘅融誒租任公司再租出去嘅話咧，噉我哋都
維保持一定嘅彈性嘅，只要嗰個業權唔係話真係放出去嘅，噉我哋都會接受呢個lease㗎。呢一方面就係希望可以達到平衡各方面嘅要求啦。因為喺飛機租用業務裏邊咧，嗰個結構咧，我structuring嗰個咧係有一定嘅複雜性。
個法例咧要有一定嘅彈性，先可以滿滿足業界要求嘅。咁呢啲噉嘅細節咧，噉我哋原則上，税務局或者政府委唔會反對。不過我諗，我哋需要喺我哋嘅誒部門嘅適宜同準則裏邊咧寫清楚，咁可以令到業界可以入到呢個regime，亦都避免咗。
好唔該嗱，我我預告下先啦。如果今日我哋即係我睇到個形勢都未必做得完呢一個嘅草案，都我唔想啊太趕啦。我我哋而家立法會嘅嗱，我亦都同各位委員講一講先啦。下一次嘅誒會議咧，委員會會議應該係五月二號。你哋唔係有？
啊！十點四十五分，五月二號嘅上晝十點四十五分，就係下一次呢一個財政委員會會議。咁希望咧，政府可以啊就團體嘅誒建議咧，作出一個書面回應，喺喺五月二號之前搞到嚟本會，就等我哋有一個時間去睇睇，亦都。
誒，首先多謝咁多位團體今日嚟啦。就我聽到咧，就係大部分都係贊成呢一個草案。不過有一點咧，頭先誒，我聽到阿趙生講咧，都係我最大嘅關注，就係話嗰個避税嘅問題，或者對香港航空嘅影響。因為嗱，如果有一啲係香港。
係啊。
嘅損失。
上木管理局去徵税嘅。
你都冇答到啊，主席，唔好意思，你冇答到個問題，就係喺呢一種安排底下，香港。
協議咧都係採取呢個方法，係極少數咧係比較舊啲嘅協議咧，唔採取呢種方法嘅。
咧兩個税務管轄區咧，就邊一税務管轄區嘅居民航空公司就歸嗰個。
你嘅飛機嚟到香港，我香港亦都唔徵旅費嘅，咁所以咧，同埋呢個咧個安排係相當簡便嘅。
冇嘢嘅，我想同大家講兩個成本。實質嘅成本就係我哋興建雲營運呢個機場，我哋好畀好多嘅錢。
某種現實啲嚟講，可以對香港更加有利。我簡單咁講，當你飛機多，當你航班多，咁呢個係對香港係更加有利。
係，啊，國家唔係咁嗰個，即係嗰個，即係個成本啊嘛，因為我哋都要有個成本嘅。譬如你話飛機多，航班多，呢個唔係建基於。
係會唔會有啦？呢個第一。個答案如果有係幾多？誒，趙局長係。係主席，其實呢個係唔會有損失，因為人哋唔收我税，畀翻我哋香港收啊嘛。咁所以我哋唔收我哋嘅。
嗯誒，經常喺香港，香港人擁有實質上嘅成日飛香港嘅，噉你係咪應該收足佢咧？噉我係想知呢一個喺税谷入邊點樣去處理呢一種嘅因加得減嘅一個做法嚇。
佢就會放棄咗另外一個税務管轄區嘅航空企業嘅徵税權嘅。即係換句話講咧，呢個係一個雙邊嘅安排，就話我嘅飛機去到你嗰度，你唔徵我税。
第二個就係嗰個代價，每一個飛機嚟香港嘅時候，我哋畀緊誒空氣污染嘅代價、噪音嘅代價等等，呢啲係個代價嚟嘅。即係我我即係大家唔好以為呢啲生意實實冇黐牙。我諗如果咁講係好危險咯。阿阿副局長，即係你。
噉就我就唔知喺呢一啲即係税務嗰個誒嗰個安排底下，會唔會只係方便咗？其實呢一啲嘅公司應該交足原税嘅，即係其實喺香港佢交曬香港應該比誒即係冇減一半嗰個税嗰個安排，只不。
趙副局長，唔該，多謝主席嗱。或者我想小心答一答，議員呢個問題啦。根據現時咧，税務雙邊嘅税務協議咧，其實有兩個藍本嘅。最主要嚟講就係一個經合組織嘅藍本嘅喺呢經合組織嘅藍本裏邊咧，其實就航空企業嗰個徵税權。
因為如果唔係咧，就相當複雜，有有時要睇一睇對方嘅法例點樣。咁所以咧，呢個經合組織嘅國際標準咧就相當簡潔。就就航空業嚟講，航空公司或者企業嚟講咧，現時差唔多，我可以講百分之九啊幾嘅嘅税，相比税務。
得個近啊！
你要用。
誒一片心紅去攞呢啲生意，同埋攞多啲飛機嚟嘅時候，都諗一諗。
係反映咗個成本，可能只係運作嘅成本，即係operating cost嚟嘅。但係你話實際上嗰個建設，
畀出嚟喺機場嘅建設同埋承受，無論環境啊、污染啊等等嘅損失之下咧。
即係賺粒糖，輸咗間廠嘅，所以我先至問一樣嘢，就係話呢一種安排會唔會加埋我哋？
對呢個叫必要之痛咧，你可以咁講，即係要當區，我講緊東湧咧，嗰啲居民就承受呢一個必要之痛。
用一啲嘅措施，一啲嘅方法去減少呢方面嘅嘅所謂成本嘅，咁睇下呢呢呢方面達唔達到一個議員嗰啲問題。係郭家賢，好短嘅啫，就係話而家個即係起降費啦，嗰部分。
然後就為咗香港嗰個利益嚇，即係唔好意思，即係即係從如果你住喺東湧嘅話，即係你喺嗰區嘅，你就明白我講嗰樣嘢。佢日日望住嗰啲飛機越嚟越多嘅升降對佢哋嘅影響。噉我希望即係政府喺即係。
我諗阿阿劉生會答一個問題啦，唔該你劉生。誒，國研嗰個範疇，因為牽涉到可能係闊少少，可能航空嗰個整個政策嚇。誒，關於嗰個成本嗰度咧，就分兩層啦。首先，誒，我哋嗰個興建成本咧，其實每一架飛機嚟香港着陸或者係起飛啦。
其實佢係需要付出誒一啲嘅費用畀機管局嘅，即係我哋所謂例如好簡單landing and parking fees噉樣樣。咁所以就誒同嗰個機本身是否即係租任嗰個税務安排咧，其實就分開嘅。即係佢話簡單嚟講，無論呢架飛機係租嘅係買嘅點樣都好咧，凡係佢用香港機場。
嘅設施咧，佢係需要畀翻嗰個成本費用嘅，咁所以就呢方面就誒未必係一個損失，可以咁講嚇。另外一啲所謂誒無形啲嘅噪音啊、誒空氣污染啊等等嗰啲咧，其實就全世界各地嘅航空公司或者我哋所謂一個世界嗰個誒誒航嗰個組織。
iCareo咧，其實佢哋都睇呢樣嘢睇得好緊嘅，咁所以佢哋不時都會發放一啲新嘅指引，誒，包括係誒，例如誒噪音點樣滅音啊，又或者而家最新可能做緊一個關於嗰個carbon emission，即係嗰個碳排放啊等等嗰啲。咁所以呢啲咧，其實所有嗰個誒航空公司或者機場咧，都會係跟隨去做。
可能埋單而家講二千億嘅錢去增加咗嗰個航班嘅升降量，而即係入邊嗰個錢咧係我相信唔係咁少嘅。即係我我我我即係如果你有數，我好歡迎有個數畀我嚟睇，就係究竟呢一啲係幾多啦。第二咧就誒，我同意嘅國際上大家去。
誒唔係冇代價畀嘅。然後第三咧就係啲飛機，我知道咧都係有啲限制，譬如Heathrow、希希斯魯噉樣，佢都對於一啲不歡迎嘅機種，佢你都知個升降時間啦，錢又唔同啦。咁噉我估咧就呢啲飛機租任公司咧就唔係全部係。
係細機嚟嘅，應該都有啲係大機嚟嘅，即係可能有啲舊機款，甚至係高排放、高污染嘅機喺將來嘅誒喺嗰個安排入邊，都會唔會係相應係要畀翻呢一啲係高排放、高污染嘅一啲多啲嘅。
嘅重價税。
Miss Liu, yes, your time.
一路好誒留心噉樣樣去monitor，即係去監察住嗰個數據。多謝多謝主席。
我諗好簡單，回覆翻國員頭先嘅提問就誒，當然嗰啲landing嘅packing charge未必係百分之一百可以收回成本，但係即係呢個我我我哋我哋個睇法就係話誒，成個機場嗰個運作咧誒。
啲啲government representative when they make the summary response， did they actually address your concern？ or you would like to further talk about that particular point a bit further？
咁令到即係我哋，即係你都有個有因，令佢係減低對成個香港或者成個地球嗰個污染啦。係啊，劉生喺你未答覆之前咧，我我我想請啊啊郭家麒議員睇一睇啊。我哋其實誒喺文件嗰度咧係有一份嘅誒文件係C B Q四八九四。
斜洞十六-hyphen十七cool零二咧，就係列出咗嗰個landing charge嘅，誒香港誒使用國際機場嚇，噉就係防運局係四月廿一號畀我哋嘅，咁呢個當然係都未能夠完全答覆到啊國家嘅議員嘅嘅問題，只不過。
我都係畀咗啲數字畀你誒。其其實呢啲噉嘅差，可能即係話二千八百蚊啊，三千蚊，究竟係計咗啲乜嘢嘅誒直接或者間接嘅成本咧？或者有冇計埋嗰個所謂社會成本咧？呢個我都留待阿阿阿劉生再向我哋解釋。唔該，劉生多謝主席誒。
主要係為咗成個香港嘅經濟服務嚇，所以誒，我哋雖然未必可以喺個landing and parking charge嗰度收得翻曬嗰個誒成本，但係誒，即係機場作為香港一個主要嘅經濟增長嘅推動引擎咧，我覺得呢個我哋必須要留意嘅誒。另外有關於例如係噪音啊。
或者嗰啲誒飛機啊嘅嘅型號啊等等嗰啲，誒我即係可以好簡單咁講，就係話誒香港機場其實佢哋有好多措施係同希斯洛機場而家做誒推行緊嘅係相類似嘅。例如我哋已經係誒不準許一啲某一啲嘅類別，即係我哋叫Chapter Three嘅嘅一啲好舊好。
嘈嘅飛機咧，我哋已經唔畀佢喺香港嗰個機場嗰度升降㗎啦嚇。咁誒呢一方面，我哋會逐步邁進啦，希望慢慢慢慢係透過唔同嘅誒市場嘅手段啊，或者係一啲行政嘅措施咧，將一啲舊嘅機種或者好嘈嘅機種咧，係慢慢淘汰嘅。誒呢一方面，亦都想個議員清知道咧，就係其實。
嗱，只要喺細節執行嘅時候。
要求有關嘅企業咧係有實體嘅經營喺香港嘅。
其實呢個係一個國際嘅標準嘅。如果有關嘅租任公司要取得喺香港雙邊信託協議網絡裏邊嘅，
Mr. Chief，嗱就頭先團體講出咧，就話嗰個佢佢用英語係講個Great Spirit，就就嗰個中央管理及控制嗰個test啦。
誒特別喺佢哋嘅submission，即係呢一紮嘅意見書裏邊咧，都有一啲係非常之清晰，係問一啲嘅問題。即係我希望誒，我覺得下一次睇下點樣係做翻一個表，或者點樣將今次團體。
There is concern about abuse of the tax regime, but again, if we were to have a more comprehensive tax concession regime, again these might be factors to consider. Okay, Mr. Tan, with some response from the government side, please. Thank you, Chairman.
我相信主席十分之願意，即係再接受你哋，譬如你哋寫翻封信入嚟，話翻我哋聽，即係究竟嗰個嘅誒税務局嗰個答答法，或者佢哋嘅做法，大家覺得係合唔合適、合唔合理？咁誒，我冇其他特別嘅問題啦，但係即係。
咁所以咧，我哋會喺睇下實質嘅環境。其實關鍵點咧，就在乎佢有冇實體嘅業務喺香港。如果有，我哋係會認定佢係中央管理及控制喺香港，亦都會考慮發出嗰個居民證畀佢，等佢可以取得喺雙邊信託協議嘅利益嘅。
其實我哋而家亦都係同航空公司係合作緊，係利用好多誒科技嘅方法，即係例如我哋誒盡量利用嗰個衞星導航嗰個技術，就係喺飛機咧令到佢飛嘅時候咧，嗰條線路係比較準確啲，咁變咗佢就唔會係因為飛歪咗咧，就會將嗰個噪音係會影響到，例如馬灣。
或者係附近地區嗰啲居民，咁呢啲我哋係不斷會做嘅，同埋馬灣噪音方面咧，我亦都可以喺度誒，即係誒，即係承諾國語原則，我哋一定會好用心咁去睇。誒，我哋有十幾個呢啲唔同嘅噪音嗰啲收集嗰啲誒誒儀器啦，喺全香港唔同嘅地方，馬灣都會有嘅。噉我哋係。
誒，我提醒各位委員咧，如果你我想嗱，下一個排住隊嘅就係阿譚文豪議員。如果你哋有問題問團體嘅時候，不妨你提出先。阿譚文豪議員，你係咪有問題？O.K.唔該。Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Um, first of all, thank you very much for every everyone come over here this morning. Unfortunately, there's three meetings going on at the same.
That's why you know some of our committee keep coming in and out. Some of the information I miss out. What I actually caught my attention was from Miss Carrie Liu when you mentioned about the capital allowance, and also you, I think, you also mentioned about the grace period.
Yeah, so it is just an observation that we have added to this whether or not there might be any room for considering a grace period. Because at the moment, once you lose the eligibility to come become a qualifying aircraft lessor, you can't opt back in.
條 regime it's a it's an absolute, so whether or not that might impact on the attractiveness of the regime, so so that's that's one aspect to consider, and then the other one is just a minor technical point about, because one of the key thing is this deduction that you get the 80% deduction that effectively gives you to to effective tax.
Tax rate of much lower than 8.25, it comes down to about 1.65. In it, it does have a limitation that says if the aircraft has been capital allowance has been claimed on the aircraft by by a associated or connected person in the past.
then you don't again qualify for a regime. And given some of the aircraft leasing group, there might be situation where the aircraft do move within the group, whether or not again, if if the aircraft do transfer at arms length value, whether or not that concern is still you know a relevant concern. And we understand that.
誒利益嘅話咧，即係簡單嚟講，就係一個低啲嘅預提税率（lower嘅holding tax）咧，噉佢需要喺個中央管理及控制係要喺香港嘅。咁呢點咧係一個國際上嘅要求嘅。噉就税基侵蝕及利用轉移咧，呢一點亦都係重要啊。因為呢一點咧就要。
等我講咗，你先回答好唔好啊？唔該。
香港佢肯定會係誒誒嚟香港開展嘅業務。
Say it out in English because it's better to to express such technical, you know.
咁所以我哋個協會裏邊咧係個成員咧都包括咗呢啲嘅國際上知名嘅租人公司嘅。
會嘅主席，好得。嗯，譚議員咧，仲冇問題問團體先，我想問一問你。
我希望即係做呢條標嘅時候做得小心啲，唔好令到誒誒一啲人。
啊，我都想問下阿阿許許先生嘅President of Hong Kong Aircraft Leasing Aviation Finance Association。
真係唔擔心，即係你話有冇公司會嚟香港做呢門生意？我覺得絕對肯定有。多謝主席。唔該曬啊，譚議員。啊，譚議員嘅建議，即係個表列形式，你哋會唔會做咧？嚇，好。
有啲團體都講到啦，嚇！實上喺個新水準裏邊嚟講啦，誒，我哋係呢個近水樓台啦，係特別係針對面對呢個國內嘅市場嚟講啦，誒，我哋睇到係好明顯嘅。
好，主席啊，唔該，誒簡單答話係有嘅，啊，即係實上我哋啊本身公司嚟講咧，已經係有業務，但係我哋呢方面嘅業務咧，而家係以外而難在呢個税基嘅。咁喺呢個知道香港政府有呢個啊。
多謝主席，我冇其他問題，唔該。好，啊唔該你。啊，我諗我有即係一兩條問題問翻啲誒議會團體嘅，誒亦都想政府回應下嘅。就求先咧，就誒應該好似係Mr. Lin咧就講過，誒有關一個如果啊，I just。
我哋係整年去睇，就唔係話睇你誒每一日都要有呢呢一點嘅噉。所以咧，我諗喺執行嘅情況之下，會有一定嘅彈性嘅。咁喺現實操作，我哋都深切體會到咧，一間企業唔可以一日咧就變成間好大嘅企業嘅。
Mr. Tim，唔該，主席。誒，另外咧，我就想誒講一講，即係我自己一直都講，我都係非常之支持呢一個嘅誒修例。我非常之支持，因為其實的而且確，主席我都曾經多次講，就係話呢一個係香港冇嘅一個生意嚟嘅，即係唔係話突然之間會帶咗好多飛機飛咗嚟香港啊，或者係。
係令到香港製造咗好多呢啲嘅生態嘅成本，唔係噉樣嘅一回事嚟。咁所以其實我好支持今次呢一個嘅修例噉，但係即係我相信咧，亦都有啲誒比較技術嘅位。即係今日我哋聽到咁多，即係有啲更加係非常之專業嘅團體嚟到講出誒一啲嘅位，究竟係誒。
佢哋畀嘅一啲係真係講緊邊一條，佢哋有個乜嘢嘅擔憂或者乜嘢意見，係可以逐項做翻一個嘅回應，咁令到團體咧遲啲你哋可以查翻，即係立法會嘅文件嚟到睇翻，究竟嗰度有冇啲咩問題。咁如果佢哋翻咗嚟，你哋都仍然覺得咦未剔除到。
其他委員都係最擔心嘅，即係會唔會利用咗呢一個位嚟到本來佢應該交一啲香港嘅税，而從而係可以走咗一啲嘅税項，呢個係係最重要嘅。咁至於你話係咪可以吸引到其他嘅誒公司喺香港嚟到嚟到做，我真係唔擔心。我相信呢條條例如果過之後，我。
即係因為我我見呢個會個名啦，所以我就喺度諗緊啊。咁其實誒，其實有冇一啲嘅公司其實已經有向你個會嚇push話啊，其實都好想即係呢個條例生效咗嘅話，佢哋真係會嚟香港。如果係個數量大，有幾間公司有揾你哋咧。簡單啲話有。
terms.
誒，你仲覺得係誒？
I think Mr Linus mentioned about a non-discriminatory article in the model treaties because.
究竟喺税制上邊咧，我哋仲有啲乜嘢係係誒個分別係大唔大，同埋係有啲乜嘢係？
Can this benefit be given to to that particular company? If it is a branch of a overseas company.
好多意見我哋啦，但我就想問一問咧，即係經過政府而家嗰個建議嘅修訂之後咧，同我哋嘅主要嘅誒競爭對手，即係爭啲生意啦，我講得白啲啊～
Mr. Lin also mentioned that, well, if the company or or the group itself wants to use a branch of a overseas company rather than incorporating a company in Hong Kong.
Obviously, central management and control is an essential criteria in deciding whether you're going to give that listed company in Hong Kong the tax benefits, but
多謝主席。誒，主席就頭先呢個問題咧，係一個相當技術性高嘅問題嘅。一般嚟講咧，就喺税務雙雙邊税務協議方面嚟講咧。
呢個新嘅政策，呢個動向嘅時候咧，我哋已經係聯絡咗好多國際上嘅大嘅租賃公司啦、租任公司啦，譬如話A.C.G啦、Gcast啦、啊呢個Air Lease啦嚇，呢個等等噉樣嘅公司咧，佢都係表達非常之大嘅興趣。事實上，可能頭先咧，我哋。
誒一個好大嘅優勢喺度。誒而家喺好多個外國嘅租任公司咧，喺進入呢個內地嘅市場嘅時候咧，誒我頭先提過啦，譬如話有幾個即係自貿區，天津啦啊或者上海啦嚇，噉佢哋係覺得嗰度咧係有好多問題啊，令到佢哋咧喺呢個誒。
進入個中國市場裏邊咧，係有一定嘅誒阻滯或者一個一個保留嘅。咁所以喺香港呢個特別又係我哋嘅法制嘅非常健全，各方面嘅服務啊，呢個連帶服務咧係非常之即係可以信賴得過。咁所以佢一致嘅睇法就係，如果有噉嘅例，可以咧。
誒，税務管理區可以就佢自己嘅居民企業咧，係畀特別嘅優惠嘅。但係與此同時咧，佢唔能夠咧係歧視非居民地嘅企業。如果咁啱同佢有一個雙邊嘅税務協議嘅，嗱喺現實嘅操作裏邊咧，就每一種嘅安排咧相。
兩個税務管理局咧，要透過個主管當局咧去釐定清楚咧，究竟係有冇歧視嘅成分噉，同埋雙方咧會唔會都認同可以噉樣做咁？所以咧喺過往我哋嘅經驗裏邊嚟講咧，就呢啲特別嘅處理，即係特別嘅處理。
方式係非居民企業嘅喺香港嘅一個支行一個branch，我哋要對同對方嘅主管當局去溝通嘅。咁個答案咧，往往未必個個case都係一致嘅，要睇下當地嘅法律同埋當地嘅政策，同埋我哋香港有關嗰個法律。
條文係同佢吻合嘅，咁先至有一定嘅結論嘅。咁呢一點我哋係留意到嘅。咁但係我諗現時嘅機制咧，我哋要透過一個叫mutual agreement procedure嘅程序去解決嘅，就唔能夠話一個blanket嘅誒誒yes or no嘅答案嘅。呢個係做唔到嘅，知唔知啊？
另外仲有一條問題，就係我請啊Presswood House嘅梁先生咧，我我據悉你哋公司係有個二零一七年誒AquaFinancing嘅誒一個報告出咗，係咪啊？請你可唔可以畀一份誒呢個委員會咧？呢份報告，好，好，好，絕對冇冇問題。依個誒二零一七年嗰份報告其實。
係誒誒，係我哋就最近搞咗一個誒飛機租任嘅研討會。噉我哋邀請咗喺香港嘅誒金融係嚟參與嘅。噉我哋係喺份報告度係反映咗入邊金融界係點樣睇政府而家推緊呢個新新措施。我哋可以。
呢個係好好嘅一個資料嚟嘅。噉啊，阿陶錦新議員，我知你係有問題，但係如果你嘅問題如果唔係直接同團體有關咧，我可唔可以誒誒請團體可以即係離席咧，唔好keep住咁耐咧？你有冇？我同佢哋有關係得咁得啦。咁計請你請你問啦嚇。誒誒，唔好意思，即係我遲咗誒嚟啦，就誒我就多謝你哋誒，即係畀。
啊！
唔同嘅誒。
咧，我哋喺唔同嘅地方，香港、誒深圳。
好，阿陶議員，你仲冇問題？我睇下其他有冇其他咪有冇阿阿何生唔該你哈。
令而令到呢個飛機租用嘅行業係更加蓬勃嘅蓬勃嘅咧，其實我誒喺我哋誒份誒。
都希望第時香港政府可以全力誒誒多啲簽多簽得多啲啲噉嘅雙邊税收協定誒嘅協議，而更加令有利於依個飛機租任行業嘅喺香港嘅發展。
誒重要嘅分別，而係誒誒，我哋係誒唔夠吸引力嘅咧，噉樣噉啊！我想聽一聽嘅嚇，係邊位想回答舉手，可以有多位嘅團體都可以答嘅。誒，你哋舉一舉手啊！阿梁生先啦，唔該你嚇。
多謝曬主席。誒，我或者我嘗試下回應啦。Baseon誒，我哋自己誒羅冰鹹嘅誒，因為我哋其實都睇咗誒依個税制好耐誒，亦都誒不嬲一一直喺度跟緊政府依個依樣政策嘅。咁其實我哋自己咧誒喺最近。
誒上海、北京都開咗好多嘅研討會，都邀請咗好多誒喺一方邊嘅業界嚟嚟參與，而我哋哋亦都解釋畀你聽，香港政府而家依一個税制係係點樣樣嘅。噉我哋只計咗好多數，頭先我喺我誒講嗰陣時候我都講咗，誒，我覺得香。
香港政府今次一個嘅誒税制嘅發展誒嚟推呢個飛機租任咧，其實對誒比較喺我哋其他嗰啲誒其他國家，譬如誒愛爾蘭或者新加坡咧，佢嗰個實質税率咧誒，雖然佢哋係唔可以畀呢個誒飛機嘅折扣，但
但係，由於誒我我噉嘅理解就係話，由於政府唔可以畀嘅飛機折扣，所以政府亦都話：誒噉我冇理由係要你哋畀翻誒百分之一百嘅税按嗰啲租金嘅，因為咁如果唔係嘅就係好唔公平嘅。咁所以我哋計數嘅時候咧，我哋我哋見到咧，我哋計咗。
因為飛誒唔同嘅租金咧，其實我哋見到咧，香港依個嘅實際税率咧，比起愛爾蘭、新加坡咧，其實係低咗好多嘅。咁而家誒，我哋留意到依個市場上入邊咁點解咁多人係做依個飛機租任咧？就係其實我哋誒中國內地或者香港嘅，其實係有。
多誒誒誒錢喺度嘅，而亦都係冇其他啲誒或者係誒好誒，即係誒咁賺錢嘅嘅嘅業務啦。咁所以好多人係係留意緊呢個飛機租任嘅。咁咁大家做到最後啦，可能發展咗幾年之後嘅，佢哋可能都係想以呢個常。
係咪？
阿陶議員，你仲有冇問題？
同呢個其他國家之間嘅雙重呢個。
能夠啊，能夠將呢個再進一步降低，我諗係呢個對個行業有時面對內地市場嚟講係更加有利嘅。多謝主席。多謝許生，有冇團體想有補充啊？
上市為一個誒誒出路噉樣啦。咁如果你上市嘅時候嘅噉，我覺得嘅睇你嗰個誒誒誒誒profit loss account咧，其實香港依個誒噉嘅推出嚟咧，係比起其他國家係好好多嘅。噉你話誒，仲有香港有咩事係可以做到而？
誒信入邊咧都都有提提及到嘅，噉我覺得改嘅税制係第一步，咁亦都希望政府第時亦都全力配合業界嚟誒向海外嗰啲誒誒飛機租賃公司或者係中國內地租賃公司誒推出依一個誒全新的税制，等佢哋知道咗。
香港政府係誒百分之一百喺誒配合誒係誒想推動呢個行業嘅。另外，我亦都覺得，因為香港頭先都有人提到，香港誒而家簽定嘅誒雙邊税收寫定，比起其他嘅國家，可能係較為少嘅。噉啊！
好喂，係多謝。嗯，就誒飛機係非常昂貴嘅資產，所以咧產生嘅收入啊租金咧都非常高，所以咧對飛機租租任公司嚟講咧誒營商環境裏邊嘅税咧非常重要嘅。嗯，根據現時嘅。
嘅計算數字咧，就如果呢一個法案可以通過嘅話咧，就誒應該係誒比較呢個愛爾蘭同新加坡咧，香港係可能更有優勢。就誒，所以咧誒，對我哋嚟講咧，業界嚟講咧，可能係誒呢個第一步。誒，另一點咧，想補充。
下咧就係亦都係非常重要嘅咧，就係誒香港同誒其他國家咧，係嗰個叫做雙邊税務協議。就誒，因為嘅飛機個租任嚟講咧，係有誒一個出租方有個承租方。誒承租方咧有好多國家咧需要。
誒誒支付一種叫做預提所得税，咁呢啲嘅雙邊税務協議咧，就係可以係處理呢啲嘅預提所得税。嚟香香港下一步咧，就需要咧更加擴大誒香港誒嘅呢個預提所得税呢個網絡。啊，呢個咧係我相信咧，香港政府。
可以下一步咧，係繼繼續支持去做嘅。係，仲有冇團體想回應㗎？舉一舉手啊！係，許生唔該你。係，我我諗啊，我就係呢個再響應或者就重複啦，就係我哋作為協會嘅角度嚟講咧，絕對認同頭先啊何生同埋啊梁生佢講其中一點，就係點樣盡快擴大香港。
呢個呢個啊，避免呢個雙重徵税，即係個D T A。咁第一步，我覺得即係相對可以比較容易啲做啦嚇。其實香港政府已經做咗啦，譬如同香港同內地之間啊啊有一個D T A。啊，本來係七個percent到減到五個percent。咁但係呢一方面嚟講咧，當然係呢個啊，就從個競爭角度嚟講咧，如果能
好噉啊！今日多謝曬各位團體啊，嚟到呢一度嚟聽證會。嗯，如果你哋對政府即係將來有啲咩回應誒，有啲咩再跟進咧，其實我我諗你可以直接啊，同我哋嘅啊秘書講講嘅嚇，或者你直接揾我亦都得嘅嚇。唔該曬各位，係噉。